Fortunately my slide will be centered, because
I'll have to change resolutions. I think this works out...
And, it's about protecting your privacy with FreeBSD and Tor
and, uh...
Privacy.
What I mean here is mostly anonymity
but there are some other aspects that
I'll talk about later
uh, so...
I want to first talk about who needs anonymity anyway
Is it just for criminals or some other bad guys, right?
After this
anonymization concepts, then Tor. Tor's a, well, a tool
to, uh...
anonymize you on the Web. Then I'll talk about what
FreeBSD can do with it
and what else
you have to take care of
when you want to be anonymous on the Web or the Internet
And uh,
if time permits I'd like to do a little demonstration
Ok, so who needs anonymity anyway?
Anonymity is a pretty vast
interest to most people
but it's really important for
journalists... There was a case in, uh,
Thailand last year
when the military coup was going on
and the journalists in Thailand couldn't really uh
Journalists couldn't really, uh
get the information they needed to do their work
Also, uh, informants
whistleblowers... people who want to tell you about
corruption going on in governments and companies
and don't want to lose their job for it... Dissidents
Uh, best case
when in Myanmar
last few weeks ago
When the
all the Buddhists monks were going to the streets and uh,
the Internet was heavily censored
It was really dangerous to do anything on the Internet
So, so umm
socially sensitive information, like when you want to uh,
when you were abused
and want to talk to other people about it
you don't... naturally you don't want other people to
know who you are
as it will be very embarrassing
Also Law Enforcement, ah
for example, uh, when you want to set up a
an anonymous tipline for crime reporting
And uh, also companies that want to, uh
research competition, as one case that, uh
that a company went to check the, uh
website competition and they noticed when they used Tor
that, uh, they were actually getting a different website
when they
uh, were coming from the corporate LAN
than anyone else was getting, so ah,
it's a good way to, uh,
check out... competition like this
Also military
actually military was one of the, uh
original
driving forces behind the
anonymization research.
And maybe you
may have heard of the European Union
Data Retention Directive?
Where, umm
collection data gets stored
six to twenty-four months? Depends on the limitation
on the different nations
Two weeks back this was, uh,
the law was passed in Germany
So, uh
from first January on,
every connection, phone connection,
SMS, IP connections,
email, or the dial-in data needs to be stored
by providers for six months
And, uh,
sooner or later it's going to be in Poland as well
[talking]
Well, you're part of the Euro Union now, so ah, welcome!
Okay, uh
that's a
Maybe you want to hide what interests you have and uh,
who you talk to, I mean uh,
like all of you know the Internet isn't very
secure in the first place so your ISP can see who you're
talking to
if they bother to find out
Yeah, and also
criminals, but they already do illegal stuff and they
don't care about
doing more illegal stuff to stay anonymous, right? They can
steal people's identities, they can rent botnets or
create them in the first place
and uh,
or just
crack one of the thousands of Windows computers online,
no big deal
So, uh
Criminals already do this and uh,
the normal
citizens can't do this so...
So all the groups that need anonymization are very different,
but they all have the same goal, and uh
that's also one of the
key concepts of
anonymization
you can't really
stay anonymous on your own
you need the help of more people
and uh,
the more diverse the group that needs
anonymity, the better
Ok, so on to talking about two
anonymization concepts
Proxy? Everyone here probably knows how a proxy works,
LANs connect to the proxy and request
a website or whatever and the proxy
just passes it on and pass through
Proxys are fast and simple but it's really a single point of
failure, like uh,
when law enforcement or anyone else wants to
uh, know
who you're talking to they just
get a subpoena or
break into the computer room or whatever
It's pretty easy
Second anonymization concept is MIX,
it's really old from nineteen eighty one
So you can see, uh,
how long the research in this area is going on
The MIX is kind of similar to a proxy
Like, trying to connect to it to send the messages
and the MIX collects them
and coalesces them
Like, it puts them all
into coming sites and uhm,
you see here it
shuffles them. It waits
until there's enough data in it and just
shuffles them and sends them back out so
um, this is to protect against correlation attacks.
But second in...
Oh yeah, and
when you actually put several MIXes uh
behind them; it's a MIX cascade and uh,
between mixes is also
encryption going on, uh, the first
or the client which
you could see here if the slides would be centered, uh,
what else gets the
public keys of all the mixes
and encrypts the message first for each of them
and each mix removes one encryption layer and
uh, the last one actually passes on the message unencrypted
and uhm, loop back backwards the same
So, as you can probably imagine,
if you wait until you have enough messages, ah, and all
public key encryption
is going pretty slow
and uh,
this concept is mostly used for
remailers like
MixMinion, for example uh
where it's not really a possib... um
it's not really important
if the message is a couple of seconds
late or something, but it's not really
great for uh, for
low latency connections,
like web routing for example
but what's good about it it's uh
distributed trust uh,
just one these MIXes has to be secure to actually
anonymize the whole connection
so it's slow but it's
distributed trust, which is good.
So, I want to introduce Tor
Tor stands for The Onion Router.
It's a concept that is actually built on
both these concepts
MIXes and proxies.
It's a TCP-Overlay network,
that means you can, uh
channel any
TCP connection through it
theoretically
Uh, theoretically I will explain
a couple of slides later
It provides a SOCKS interface so you don't need any uh,
special application proxies like any application that uses
SOCKS interface can just
talk to Tor
and it's available on, um, all major platforms
What is uh, especially important it's available in Windows
Because, uhm, like I said earlier once
you want a really diverse,
really diverse group of users
so you actually need uh,
the normal user
not just geeks.
Um, well it aims to uhm
combine the positive attributes of
proxies and MIXes
Like, proxies are fast, but
seem prone to failure
and MIXes
distributed trust, you want to combine them
so uh
Fast, uh, Tor uses not only public key
encryption but also session keys
so it's symmetrically encrypted.
So uh
all the connection set up is this public key so you just, uh
authentication and stuff
And uh, the actual communication that's going on later
is always symmetrically encrypted
And uh, so it's also TCP multiplexing
so you can run
several TCP connections through one
virtual Tor connection.
And the design goals are
yeah
deployability
like dums want the user to actually have
to patch his PC off the Operating System or something
just be in a... workable state really fast.
Um, usability,
so you get the uh,
normal users
not just the geeks. Flexibility, uhm
it's aimed to
enable more research
in this whole area.
So, uh
the protocol Tor users
should be really flexible
And uh, for simplicity it's a security application and
well complexity doesn't play well with uh,
security
So, this uh,
it's how Tor works, more or less
Dave is uh, a directory server,
it uh, caches information about the network state
and uh, which Tor servers are available in the network
and uh
Alice downloads
this whole list from Dave
you see the Tor nodes with the plus here?
Through this random
tree of service
when she wants to talk to Jane
for example
The first one is the entry node, middleman nodes, and the
uh exit nodes, I will leave these for later
uh, so this
Alice talks to the entry node
there's a connection that is going on and is public key
encrypted
and they establish a session key and same
thing goes on
between these two and these two so they can communicate
later on
What's really important here
is the last connection here
is actually unencrypted.
I will talk about it later
So it has to be unencrypted
so you can actually get your request through
This is a virtual circuit
that gets established and uh
every, every
ten minutes
a new circuit is built
when a new website, when a new request comes through, so uh
this one stays, all these connections above stay
in this circuit
and after ten
when after ten minutes, ah
Alice wants to talk to Jane, a new circuit is built
and uh, this is important
to get strong
anonymity
in case one connection is compromised, for example.
And these ten minutes
are really an arbitrary value,
you can choose anything
you have to do the research
which value is best and so
ten minutes is compromised.
With Tor you get exit policies,
this is important for the exit node
the one which actually sends the uh,
original request to the destination server
and huh
you can control which
TCP connections you want
to allow from your own node if you want
As default policy which uh
blocks SMTP and NNTP to prevent uh
spamming and all stuff
but you can actually allow
SMTP if you want
and there's some other ports blocked
but the rest of it works so
HTTP SSH
all the important stuff
that you would want to anonymize just works
and uh, if you uh
this is important for uh, if you
want to run you own node, uh
what kind of node you actually want to run
if you look at the picture, uh earlier
there's these three different nodes: entry node,
middleman node, and exit node
and uh, which node you want to run
depends on how many problems you want afterwards
I will talk about it later uh
this one,
the exit node actually forwards the uh, requested date, uh
depends upon what
what the user actually uh wants, that's
if the user uh
Alice in this case uh
insults someone out on a web forum, then uh the uh
administrator of the forum will see the IP address
of the
exit node in his logs and not the one
of Alice so uh he's going to have the problems later on
so I will talk about it later
but you have to keep this in mind
And uh, keep up everything and uh we can play the role of
entry nodes and middleman nodes
which is also important
Special feature of Tor are hidden services
these are services which can be
accessed
without having the IP address of them
so uh
you can't really find them physically
So if you want to run a
hidden service you can do it from anywhere
You can even do it from inside this private network here
You can set up a service and everyone in the outside world
can actually access it
even if you don't have the rights to do
port forwarding or something
uh, this is really important to, uh
resist Denial of Service, for example
Because every uh,
every client that wants to
access the service uh,
gets a different route in the network
and uh, it's hard
to actually uh
DOS it. And it's also important to
resist censorship
And the addresses look like this:
it's really a hash of a public key
and each hidden service is actually, well, identified
by a public key
This how it works, uhm, yet Alice the client
and the hidden server, Bob.
And if Bob wants to, uh,
wants to set up a service,
he chooses three introduction points
out of the whole mass
of Tor servers.
And Bob has the public key to identify the service,
and uh he sends
this public key and the list of three introduction
points to the directory server.
Now Alice wants to uh,
connect to Bob, the first the first thing she does
is download this
this list with the introduction points and the uh
public key from the directory server. After that, uh
she chooses one of the uh introduction points
and uh,
posts a circle rendezvous cookie there. A piece of
data so uh, she can, uh
identify herself
and uh, she also
gives the introduction point
the address of her random rendezvous point that
Alice has chosen
so what happens then is uh, Bob notices that uh,
some data has been stored in the introduction point
and Alice and Bob uh,
make a rendezvous point, and
Bob uses this, this uh
rendezvous cookie to
actually identify himself on the rendezvous point
and after that
all the connection of data runs through this rendezvous point.
uh, if time permits I'll actually uh,
set up a rendezvous
a hidden service here
so you can actually see how it works
I'll also demonstrate Tor, like I said
uh, there's some legal issues to be uhm
recognized, uh. As you can imagine, Tor may be
forbidden in some
countries; especially totalitarian countries
which censor the Internet anyway
and uh,
you may get into trouble for using Tor
practically, anyone knows this
there can be crypto restrictions
for example Great Britain, the uh
RIPA act, I'm not even sure what it stands for
but basically says that uh,
if the government wants,
then you have to give up your crypto keys
so they can decrypt it later
and uh, yeah, it's not really great
and actually last week was the first case
when this was actually used in
Great Britain
Uh, there can be special laws like in Germany
sort of like a hacker paragraph
It's just a nickname, it has some cryptic legal name
uh, in reality
and it says that uh
you're liable if you, uh,
if you give people access to tools
that they can use to uh,
well, to do illegal stuff.
More or less.
It's really uh,
not concrete and no one really...
it could uh,
it could
restrict anything. From a map to a
to God know what Network tools.
and uh
But it was actually, it was actually passed so no one
really knows
what's the, uhm
what's really
restrict by it. So Tor could be restricted
by it, because it could really enable people to do
illegal stuff,
but no one really knows
and uh, the biggest Tor
problem is
that, uh
when uh, when it actually gets sent to a Tor network
the uh, the
IP address that
gets sent
well that's what the destination server
actually sees
is one of the exit nodes.
So when, uh
when a client
actually causes trouble,
then the one
that gets into trouble
is the exit nodes provider. And uh,
so stuff that gets done
for torment purpose like sending ransom mails or uh,
distributing illegal stuff
and it, this all happened
and, if you are
unlucky as an exit node operator
your server gets seized or something
and uh,
that's random stuff that can happen
So uh,
as an exit nodes provider you can get
letters from Law Enforcement agencies, and uh
What are you doing there?
Maybe some illegal stuff?
And you have to explain to them that you are
providing Tor server and
it wasn't you
and stuff.
For example the FBI
in America
actually knows what you're talking about when you tell them
that you're using Tor...
so, uh
they won't bother.
But in Germany the uh,
Law Enforcement agencies, actually are, so so
depends on what kind of guy you're actually talking to
So what's... What kind of role plays FreeBSD here?
uh, FreeBSD is really well suited as a Tor node, uh
when you're operating the client you just want to use the
network, uh
it doesn't matter what kind of system you use
and it shouldn't matter
This is one of the, uh
like I said earlier one of the design
criteria of Tor
so it doesn't matter if you're using Windows or FreeBSD.
But if you're using the Tor
as actually uh,
the security of others depends on your node
and uh,
when you're operating a node is important to
have Operational Security
and Jails
are really great for this,
so you can run a Tor server in Jail.
It's also Disk and Swap encryption
which is important, especially the swap encryption. And uh,
there's also audit
and the MAC framework
when you want to run your installation
What's also nice,
Tor servers do a lot of public key encryption
and it's pretty slow
so it's great to have
hardware acceleration for this.
And uh, probably the biggest feature:
Well maintained Tor-related ports.
There is the main port, security/Tor
Which is a client and server if you want to run
a network node, or just a client.
There's tor-devel
and these are really up to date, uhm
Tor development happens really fast
and the ports get updated
pretty soon after a release is made.
There's Privoxy, which is an uhm web proxy and uhm,
we'll use it later when we do the demonstration
And there's net management Vidalia which is a
graphical frontend
also for Windows
and, uhm
there's trans-proxy-tor
which enables you to actually
uhm, well there's some
badly written applications out there
that do stuff that's
that makes it hard for Tor to
anonymize them
and you can use trans-proxy-tor
to tunnel such connections through the Tor network.
We'll actually talk about them in the next slide.
Yeah. What else do you need to take care of
besides running Tor?
Uh, there's name resolution, uh...
Some applications just
bypass the configured proxy
for example Firefox versions below version 1.5,
which send every data,
all data through the proxy
but not
DNS requests
so they actually result in mistrust
and uh, so yeah
the connection is actually anonymized
but the DNS server
really knows
uh, who you were talking to
and this is really the intention of Tor, but uh,
newer versions actually takes.
Uh, there's the usual
cookies, web-bugs, referrer and stuff, uhm
which uh,
sites can use to check which
websites you're visiting, and it's just the
usual disabling stuff
Privoxy is a great tool to
normalize HTTP traffic.
And it's also great to uhm, well filter off advertising
and stuff.
This should be really obvious
but apparently is not. Uhm,
There's so many people who don't realize
that the last connection
chain is actually unencrypted
if you're using, uh
if you're not using a secure protocol.
So,
people actually uhm,
get their mail through POP3 or something
and the exit nodes can just run desniff and sniff
out all the passwords.
And it's really surprising how many people uh, do this.
So, lesson learned: use secure protocols.
There are also other services that require
registration, for example,
with your e-mail address or
personal
data
and uh, well
if you're using Tor and you
actually log on to one of those services, Tor can help you
So, once I actually demonstrate how
this all works.
Uh, I've installed Tor and
Privoxy on this system
Config files are on the usual places.
And if you read this, this little... small...
Is this alright?
So there is this torrc sample file
which we can use
so this
there's the usual commands and stuff
and this,
much stuff that we don't need for the moment
there's this uh,
SOCKS port and SOCKS listen address information
that just
tells you where to connect your uh,
your proxy to
so this is the information that we use in Privoxy to
access Tor.
Uhm,
all we have to do to actually use Tor is
copy over the config file.
Start the service
so, it tells us it's running... Now we have to
take a look at Privoxy
There's also lots of stuff that we don't need
right now
What we need is the uh,
we need to tell
Privoxy uh,
where to send connection requests.
Ok, I've actually entered this earlier
uhm,
all it says is uh,
forward all requests to
the uh, SOCKS client
So we just start
Ok, so we are all set
Now we can just do
everything with our browser
Startup time sucks a bit
because of my external drive
okay, uh
proxy settings
we just put in our Privoxy server
which listens on port 3128, hopefully, or doesn't?
Oh, 8108, that's it.
Ok, so every
connection we want to make should actually be routed
through the Tor network
uhm, this is going to take a little bit,
Because all the route selection needs to be done
all the public crypto, there's also network latency
Once the connections are actually setup
it's pretty fast, not like this
and it's uh, really dependent upon uh,
which
kind of nodes you get
if you have a node that is running a modem then,
you'll have problem, it's really slow
Ok, while waiting
we can actually take a look
at how our hidden service is configured
There's some lines for the Tor config file
the routing services
Ok, so you can see here hidden services here and
hidden service port
as I said, the hidden service is identified by a
public key, and uh, if you
uncomment this stuff,
and uh,
we start Tor
quickly
generate a public key and put it into the start tree
and it will, uh, well it actually says to uh,
where this omni address earlier,
we'll just
route every connection through this address to this
local nodes line
This could be the case that uh,
that an exit node
doesn't uh,
allow DNS
Ok, this is typical that when you want to show stuff
it doesn't work
It worked earlier, so uh, it's not the network's fault
let's uh,
back to the hidden services
So we actually need to
change this
The default directory in FreeBSD is /var/db/tor
and uh,
and when we start Tor it will actually, uh
create the service directory
by itself. It's also a web server listening on port 80
on localhost
so we can
and hopefully will be able to see it later on
Okay, so let's see if
this stuff is already
actually created.
Ok, so you have
two parts in this directory
hostname and private key. Private key is uh,
self-explanatory
and the hostname is actually what you give to people
if you want to
to publish your service
This is actually less likely to work right now
because it takes some time for Tor to choose these
introduction points,
send all this stuff to directory services
It takes time for directory services to sync up
and actually distribute information to the clients
and when we want to access the service, we actually put
this address into the uh,
the address line, and uh,
Tor knows how to
deal with this uh, the Onion top-level domain, so uh
this usually actually works. Let's see what's going on here...
Well, like I said
this one will take a while and
what's going on with the other one? I can actually see
But uh,
usually you can just go to one of these server websites
that tell you your IP address, and
Google is a fair example
you can go to Google and Google will get you a
localized web page.
For example, when you are from Germany, and you go to
google.com, you get a German webpage
and if you're using Tor and you go to Google,
it depends
upon where your exit point is located
for example,
if it is in the Netherlands,
you get a Dutch Google, which is uh, pretty cool.
So uh,
I'll have to take a look later
while I'm working
So let's just, continue for a moment
Ok, to summarize, uh
Tor is actually useful if
you want to be hidden on the net. If it actually works.
Not in this case, uh
Tor is usually pretty cool to offer services from anywhere
so theoretically
it should work
that I
publish my hidden service around here
and anyone in the world that's connected to the Tor network
can actually access it
and uh
FreeBSD is a pretty cool platform for Tor
Because it has very nice
security features like jail
and if you want to run a Tor node
and uh,
tools like Tor are really needed
in our time
this isn't going
to get better any time soon; so uh, we better
create the tools now
to circumvent this
Take a quick look at the uh browser again
currently the uh,
connection set up failed
which I can't do anything about right now.
uh, which one?
Oh, that's all me
uhm
it depends upon
you can use any port you like
It depends on uh,
what port the nodes use. Nodes can use any port
for example, when I don't want to run nodes
I can put it on pause
port 80 if you want
so anyone who uh
who has uh
HTTP access can actually access my node
so uh
In theory uh
you can use any port you like.
So, this isn't going to work.
Maybe I'll just uh,
if anyone is interested, I'll just try again later
That's port 80
it's a you know, HTTP connection so,
So, are there any questions?
Yes?
Well, usually I use Opera, so
I didn't know
Yes, there are about 300 uh,
I think about
300 Tor servers around the world
No, it's uh correct
at the moment there are three directory servers
worldwide
you can recognize them by their public key
and their public keys are
hard coded into the source code at the moment
so, the uh
Tor developers actually run those directory servers
but this is really critical infrastructure
uhm
Well it's it's hard to say
Because the question was uh
Were there any estimates on uh,
net usage and other stuff
it's really hard to say because it's an anonymization
network so uh,
you can't say for sure, but there are estimates of
one hundred thousand users around the world
and uh, I'm not sure of the traffic.
I used to run a middleman node,
and in one month
it would make
it was on a one hundred megabits
or dedicated line,
and it made about one terabyte of traffic
so it's a lot of traffic
going on
and unfortunately also a lot of filesharing systems
which it doesn't really make sense because they're slow
So uhm,
Tor is really cool
for web browsing and stuff
but if you really want to move a lot of data it's
not a good tool
Ah, any other questions? Doesn't seem to be the case. Ok!